Register of the Bernice Miller papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Bernice Miller papers
1940-1979
53001
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes, 6 oversize boxes, 5 envelopes, 1 medal (4.2 linear feet)
Photographs, letters, pamphlets, and clippings relating primarily to the political and other public activities of Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover.
Miller, Bernice.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1953.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Personal secretary to President Herbert Hoover.
Scope and Content of Collection
Photographs, letters, pamphlets, and clippings relating primarily to the political and other public activities of Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover.
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944.; United States--Politics and government--1929-1933.
- Correspondence, 1942-1979
  - Dydo, Joan, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Farley, James, 1967 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Glenn, 1979 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1942-1964 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Kathy, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Miller, Herbert J., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Peggy, 1964 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Quaal, Ward L., 1964 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Rosen, Jack, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Sullivan, Lawrence, 1966 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Sullivan, Mark, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Walker, Virginia, 1961 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- Printed Matter, 1940-1975
  - Addresses, 1947-1965
    - "The Gridiron Dinner" by Herbert Hoover, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - "A Proposal for Greater Safety for America: The Assurance That We Are Not in the Decline and Fall of the American Way of Life" by Herbert Hoover, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - "Some Observations on Current American Life" by Herbert Hoover, 1960 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - "A Tribute to Herbert Hoover" by W. C. Mullendore, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Autographs, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
    Scope and Contents note
    Contains several scraps of paper autographed by Herbert Hoover.
  - Clippings, 1940-1975
    - 1940 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - 1945 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - 1946 (Box-folder 1: 18-19)
    - 1947 (Box-folder 1: 20)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 1: 21)
    - 1948 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1949 (Box-folder 2: 2-3)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - 1956 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - 1962 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - 1963 (Box-folder 2: 7)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - 1974 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 2: 12)
    - Undated (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Essays, 1944-1961
    - "A Birthday Letter to Herbert Hoover" by Lewis L. Strauss, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Bonnievale" by G. Spencer Compton, undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Hannah and Kalgoorlie" by G. Spencer Compton, undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Let's Go Fishin'" by unknown, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - "Men Are Equal Before Fish" by unknown, 1951 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Invitations, 1949-1974 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Maps, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Notes, 1946-1963 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Pamphlets, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Postcards, undated (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Press releases, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Programs, 1949-1971 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Serial issues, 1949-1972
    - CRB Alumni News, 1958 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Fortune, 1949 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Monographs, 1962-1970
    - Herbert Hoover: A Biography of Uncle Bert, the Uncommon Man by Hulda Hoover McLean, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Herbert Hoover of West Branch by Ray Sweigert, Jr., undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Herbert Hoover Oral History: Interview with Bernice Miller, 1966 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - True Greatness: The Story of a Quaker President by a Quaker by Ruth Milhous, undated (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - The Story of the Bible by Bernice Miller, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Men and Decisions by Lewis L. Strauss, 1962 (Box 3, Box 4)
      Two copies: one with a cover and one without a cover.
- Scrapbooks, undated
  - Volume I, undated (Box 5)
    Titled "Mrs. Herbert Hoover, 'American Through and Through'."
  - Volume II, undated (Box 6)
  - Volume III, undated (Box 7)
  - Volume IV, undated (Box 8)
  - Volume V, undated (Box 9)
  - Volume VI, undated (Box 10)
- Memorabilia and Ephemera, undated
  - Medal (Memorabilia cabinet)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 4)
    Contains coins, pins, medals, and a cardbox embossed with Herbert Hoover's seal, given as a Christmas gift from Hoover to Bernice Miller. Also includes miniature books of Dwight Eisenhower's inaugural address and Queen Elizabeth II's coronation.
- Photographs, 1946-1979
  - Various photographs and a photo album titled "Policemen's Ball,", undated (Envelope A)
  - 1946 trip taken by Herbert Hoover and an event for the 90th anniversary of Bohemia Club, 1946-1979 (Envelope C)
  - Herbert Hoover's 90th birthday, a 1958 trip to Brussels, and Christmas, 1958-1964 (Envelope D)
  - Herbert Hoover's birthday, the Key Largo Anglers' Club, a portrait of Hoover, and fishing trips, 1964 (Envelope E)
  - Oversize photographs of Herbert Hoover and a photograph signed by Richard Nixon and the crew members of Apollo 11, Buzz Aldrin, Neil Armstrong, and Michael Collins, 1969 (Envelope mB)